<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
    <title>Marshall Mallicoat</title>
    <link>http://marshallmallicoat.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://marshallmallicoat.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description></description>
    <language>en</language>
    <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 13:46:36 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 13:46:36 -0400</lastBuildDate>

    
    <item>
      <title>Moving Sidewalks</title>
      <link>http://marshallmallicoat.com/2015/10/04/moving-sidewalks.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>MM</author>
      <guid>http://marshallmallicoat.com/2015/10/04/moving-sidewalks.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;audio controls=&quot;controls&quot; preload=&quot;metadata&quot;&gt;
&lt;source src=&quot;/media/Moving Sidewalks.mp3&quot; type=&quot;audio/mpeg&quot;&gt;
Sorry, your browser failed to load the HTML5 audio player.
&lt;/audio&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/media/Moving Sidewalks.mp3&quot;&gt;Download here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blue Limousine</title>
      <link>http://marshallmallicoat.com/2015/09/06/blue-limousine.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>MM</author>
      <guid>http://marshallmallicoat.com/2015/09/06/blue-limousine.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;audio controls=&quot;controls&quot; preload=&quot;metadata&quot;&gt;
&lt;source src=&quot;/media/Blue Limousine.mp3&quot; type=&quot;audio/mpeg&quot;&gt;
Sorry, your browser failed to load the HTML5 audio player.
&lt;/audio&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/media/Blue Limousine.mp3&quot;&gt;Download here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prelude</title>
      <link>http://marshallmallicoat.com/2015/08/02/prelude.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>MM</author>
      <guid>http://marshallmallicoat.com/2015/08/02/prelude.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;audio controls=&quot;controls&quot; preload=&quot;metadata&quot;&gt;
&lt;source src=&quot;/media/Prelude.mp3&quot; type=&quot;audio/mpeg&quot;&gt;
Sorry, your browser failed to load the HTML5 audio player.
&lt;/audio&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/media/Prelude.mp3&quot;&gt;Download here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vanitas</title>
      <link>http://marshallmallicoat.com/2015/07/15/vanitas.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>MM</author>
      <guid>http://marshallmallicoat.com/2015/07/15/vanitas.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grave Plots&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My parents came into a couple grave plots. (I don&amp;rsquo;t know how.) They&amp;rsquo;re trying to flip them, since they already have spots reserved. They say that the cemetery in question isn&amp;rsquo;t as desirable as it used to be, so they want to unload them fast. Especially since cremation is getting more popular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mom on cremation: &lt;em&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t amount to much.&lt;/em&gt; Just a two-pint Ziploc. She dumped her mother&amp;rsquo;s ashes illegally off the Pacific coast, by where the &lt;em&gt;Twilight&lt;/em&gt; movies were shot. The remainder was pressed into a bead that she keeps on her Pandora bracelet. (This one aside, she has about $1300 in charms on it.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notice&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve come to understand the things I&amp;rsquo;ve left at my parents&amp;rsquo; house, since moving out, as &lt;em&gt;horcruxes.&lt;/em&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ll keep them there safe&amp;mdash;my old t-shirts and books&amp;mdash;in case I&amp;rsquo;m cut down in the street. (Tho if I was hit by a car tomorrow, this and everything else on my computer would be lost forever.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month I had to delete the first dead person from my email contacts: an old boss, aged 66, a Marlboro man. Put into the bin and then the bin emptied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I received a Google Alert when my grandfather&amp;rsquo;s Obits4Life page went live, since I was listed among the bereft. My inheritance remains obscure. It&amp;rsquo;s like I was left a set of shoe trees, but threw them out, not knowing what they were for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Old Man Mallicoat&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan to bald gracefully. I&amp;rsquo;ll keep it real short and see if I can slide by for a couple decades. If it gets too bad, I&amp;rsquo;ll shave it all off and be done with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My eye doctor says that, if I keep using computers, my eyes will slowly get worse and worse forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My dentist says that I grind my teeth in my sleep, probly due to my stress. So now I go to sleep in shorts and a mouthguard like a boxer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a weekend in the city, I&amp;rsquo;ll have black snot and my fingers will be swollen red around the nail. I feel like my body is already rotting. Like I&amp;rsquo;m being fitted for the big &amp;amp; tall in the sky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my wake, lay me out on a California king. Run my obituary in the &lt;em&gt;Kansas City Star&lt;/em&gt;, my preferred newspaper of record.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vanity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My desk dictionary memorializes Christopher Columbus as thus: &lt;em&gt;1451-1506 Ital. navigator; disc. Am.&lt;/em&gt; I doubt my legacy will be abbreviated so succinctly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They think Los Angeles will been underwater in 100 years. I estimate I&amp;rsquo;ve eaten 4800 peanut butter sandwiches in my lifetime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bell peppers change color from green to yellow or orange and then to red. I suspect this is the original metaphor for traffic lights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Implicit in everything I write here is the assumption that the world has never ended. Now that it’s been said, I don’t know why that seemed like such a statement to make.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Henry</title>
      <link>http://marshallmallicoat.com/2015/06/21/john-henry.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>MM</author>
      <guid>http://marshallmallicoat.com/2015/06/21/john-henry.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Emails from your boss, written in the form of a question, with a period at the end&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smart people are house slaves to the rich. Even among the aliens, the Nordic whites rule over the little greens and grays. To my landlord, I am an encumbrance on the property. To my employer, a capital outlay. I find it hard to believe that, in three million years of fossil record, there is not a single lizard man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some open questions: Why does the cable company need my Social Security number? Why does my boss need to know my credit score? How come I can&amp;rsquo;t give &lt;em&gt;him&lt;/em&gt; a piss test? Where do cows get their calcium, if they only eat grass? And their protein, for that matter?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spy satellites are so high up, they always look straight down. If you face forward, they can only see the top of your head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found a spot behind the security desk at the mall where I can watch the guards idly browse the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;John Henry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To survive in white collar labor, you must cultivate a certain lassitude, and wear it as a suit of armor. If the work load is heavy, you have to drag your feet, since even if you finish early you won&amp;rsquo;t get sent home. If the work load is light, you have to pretend to be working hard or you will get assigned more work. In any case, you must also appear to be having a good time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the railroads were built, work songs were sung to set the pace of labor. It kept everyone working at a level of exertion that could be kept up all day in the hot sun without risking death. It also kept every working at the same rate, so no one could foolishly work harder to win the graces of the foreman&amp;mdash;which would force everyone else to work harder, and thereby endanger both their welfare and their lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the office, there&amp;rsquo;s no sound other than the dull hum of the air conditioner and the cricketsong of computers. And your coworkers are all blood doping&amp;mdash;cranking on the commute, then drinking themselves to sleep at night. How can you keep up without joining in?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John Henry was able to beat the steel-driving machine thru sheer effort. But afterward, his heart gave out and he soon died. The &amp;ldquo;Ballad of John Henry&amp;rdquo; says “That old hammer killed John Henry / but that old hammer won&amp;rsquo;t kill me”. I&amp;rsquo;m saying, that old hammer won&amp;rsquo;t kill me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not an apartment, but a dark hole I lived in for 3 years&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To vacate an apartment without incident feels like getting away with a crime. You drag your mattress down the stairwell and leave it in a dumpster like a warm body. Having recouped the full deposit, you skip town before the landlord gets wise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To live is to be in constant fear of legal retribution: speeding, jaywalking, illegal downloading, cheating on your taxes, and so on. The state of Connecticut defines “loitering” as: standing around, moving slowly about, spending time idly, sauntering, dallying, lingering, or lagging behind. In Florida, twenty grams is a felony.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Say you found a pair of crystal antlers. How could you explain having a pair of crystal antlers to the police? Better to play it safe and quickly dispose of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever you hear sirens, you think it&amp;rsquo;s for you. When you see a cop, you think &amp;ldquo;so this is how it ends&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s only a matter of time before the black helicopters swoop down to snatch you up. As for me, I know my last days will be described as &lt;em&gt;brazen&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Junkie, don&#39;t talk to me</title>
      <link>http://marshallmallicoat.com/2015/05/09/junkie.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>MM</author>
      <guid>http://marshallmallicoat.com/2015/05/09/junkie.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cold water after black coffee is like tempering steel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve come to a calm in the midst of my mid-morning coffee&amp;mdash;my first and only coffee of the day. The fog in my head burns off. The wool-legged spiders who cobweb my attic disperse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Caffeine doesn&amp;rsquo;t bring euphoria&amp;mdash;more like an elasticity to your limbs and a humming in your head, from the amplified sound of your blood. And a feeling like being wrapped in warm, clean towels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it&amp;rsquo;s only good for the first few sips. Just as you start to enjoy the high, you&amp;rsquo;ve already peaked. By the time you finish, you&amp;rsquo;re past the plateau and down in the valley after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nowadays I&amp;rsquo;m only happy for 15 minutes at a time, followed by a headache. And with it comes boredom. Not a boredom like watching paint dry, but watching paint that had recently dried. The grass growing in the lawn has stalled out, and I&amp;rsquo;m languishing in a terminal middle-class lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taking dexedrine at 2am in NYC to hold you thru till 5am when Grand Central re-opens and you can get a train back to Connecticut&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d say, if caffeine was a taxi conducting your body thru the human traffic, that dexedrine is a black sedan speeding thru a tunnel at night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Junkie&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can tell when my mom has been drinking coffee. She is jubilant. She is effervescent. She &lt;em&gt;bubbles&lt;/em&gt;. I tell her, &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t talk to me, junkie.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She started drinking coffee because she was narcoleptic and would fall asleep while driving. I only started drinking coffee after I started taking caffeine pills. Which I only took with alcohol, to make drinking less miserable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read an insightful observation somewhere, maybe in a Gawker comment, that Lindsay Lohan wasn&amp;rsquo;t a cokehead, just an alcoholic who took cocaine to be able to drink more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coffee as ideology&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re in the city and there&amp;rsquo;s coffee to buy. Either with brunch or after when you walk around the shops. Later there&amp;rsquo;s beer. Someone&amp;rsquo;s in town for a few days or it&amp;rsquo;s a going away party. You drink and talk and make plans to meet at the new brunch place in the morning. They have the best espresso.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The pass code for the bathroom at the Union Square Starbucks on July 4, 2014 was 8282. And I gave it away to the first person I saw: a Russian tourist standing in line. In turn, she gave it to the people behind her. In this way, she was my first apostle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I prefer the discretion of pill poppers and day drunks to the perverts who go to cafes after dark.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hairy Man&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the March 2014 issue of &lt;em&gt;The Red Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;, an interview with Nicolas Cage (“Being Nicolas Cage”) opens with “Do you think about death?” (He does.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the grocery store by the energy drinks, there is a sign that says &amp;ldquo;This area is monitored by Closed Circuit Television.&amp;rdquo; In the aisle by the safety razors, the same sign, plus a sliding plastic shield across the shelf&amp;mdash;presumably to slow you down when scooping them into your trash bag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The implication is that there exists a cohort of congenitally hairy men (or one Hairy Man) who both fiends for caffeine and is willing to do anything to alleviate his condition.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dolphins in the Black Sea</title>
      <link>http://marshallmallicoat.com/2015/04/07/dolphins-in-the-black-sea.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>MM</author>
      <guid>http://marshallmallicoat.com/2015/04/07/dolphins-in-the-black-sea.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Istanbul&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This last month I went to Istanbul to visit my friend. He&amp;rsquo;s been living there since October. The flight took 10 hours by Turkish Airlines. (They served two meals, which were surprisingly good. They also allow up to two free checked bags. It was not half the sweaty, claustrophobic nightmare ride that it could have been. I would recommend this airline.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Istanbul is split between Europe and Asia by the Bosphorus strait. I had never been to either continent before. I can tell you Istanbul is cleaner than New York City, with less people begging for money on the street. It&amp;rsquo;s very pretty with the ocean and old buildings, and it&amp;rsquo;s good for walking. I would describe it as European, but again I&amp;rsquo;d never been in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The food is cheap and the rent is moderate in Usonian terms. The quality of life is HIGH, if not the standard of living. People eat lots of yogurt and drink lots of tea (with sugar cubes). There is a ferry to ride on. Good jackets and dark hair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More Istanbul&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some places there are so many stray cats that it becomes &lt;em&gt;comical&lt;/em&gt;&amp;mdash;like a soft PUNK&amp;#39;ing. The stray dogs are tagged and lie around on the sidewalk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are men who pick thru the trash for useful things&amp;mdash;purses, shoes, books, appliances&amp;mdash;and take them around on carts for people to buy, like a moving thrift shop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They have pay bathrooms in public places. I stole a shit (which would have cost ~$0.40) by tailgating someone who had paid before me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People drink bottled water there. An anecdote: My Indian landlady came to the US in 2009. At first she couldn&amp;rsquo;t drink the tap water; the taste of the chlorine would make her sick. So she could only drink bottled water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In public, I like to pretend I&amp;rsquo;m an ethnic white person, Ukrainian or maybe Moldovan, who comes from a hard life of cell phone sales. I don&amp;rsquo;t really act any different. It&amp;rsquo;s mostly how I hold my jaw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A thinky thing I thot&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone was well dressed, tourists from every country on Earth: good leather shoes or sneakers, well fitting pants, nice jackets, smart phones and cameras. Everyone eating at the cafe, shopping for clothes, etc. All wealthy, self-loving consumerists, as vulgar as any American.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one really gives a shit. Not the European or the Arab or the Asian. Definitely not the Turk selling “selfie sticks” for 300% markup, or the one with blister packs of Viagra outside the Grand Bazaar. You can see foreign men strolling around with blood coming thru the bandages on their scalp, pleased as hell with their new hair plugs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Travel is a luxury psychedelic, a chance to practice the word for &lt;em&gt;coffee&lt;/em&gt; in a new language. The human is happy enough to stay in their home village for their entire life. I might as well never leave the country again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on sports</title>
      <link>http://marshallmallicoat.com/2015/03/02/thoughts-on-sports.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>MM</author>
      <guid>http://marshallmallicoat.com/2015/03/02/thoughts-on-sports.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Golf&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inner workings of a miniature golf course amount to a secret gospel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Miniature golf is to golf what reality TV is to reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In golf, you swing lowercase L&amp;rsquo;s at the tops of semicolons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the bowling alley, they give you golf pencils to keep score.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My grandfather owned both a set of clubs and a bowling ball. My father has neither.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve invented a new drink that&amp;rsquo;s half-Arnold Palmer and half-Shirley Temple, called the LBJ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guessing a woman&amp;rsquo;s age is a kind of golf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other Sports&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Baseball is basically unwatchable, but it works on the radio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The counter-insurgency is Whac-a-Mole, the drug war Three-card Monte.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Capitalism has wrought the moneyballing of everything. The Dutch work 6 hours a day, then ride bikes home. Americans work for 6 hours, spend 2 hours on Facebook, then crawl thru traffic for 45 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone who sits very still at a desk all day, looking at small numbers on a screen, is a kind of athlete. It takes endurance. You need training and preparation to do it without hurting yourself. These are grown men with all the hair rubbed off their ankles by socks and prostates the size of clenched fists. They will show you their game face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The highest compliment you can pay a man is to call him a machine. Men strive to make themselves into weapons. This is done thru emotional distance, rituals of control, and repetition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On Sportsmanship&lt;/strong&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was a high school wrestler for one day. I was on the swimming team but quit. After failing to induce vomiting in the bathroom, I lied about having vomited to get out of practice. At a strip mall dojo, I put my fist thru the drywall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In job interviews, I extemporize on my temperament as if I were a race horse. As long as they let me down easy, I don&amp;rsquo;t care if I don&amp;rsquo;t get a call back. To be listed among the also-rans is enough for me. I&amp;rsquo;m like a retired greyhound who&amp;rsquo;s too skinny to lie down on hardwood floors. I understand back pain&amp;ndash;what I lack is &lt;em&gt;context&lt;/em&gt; for my back pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saw a picture of the man with the biggest hands in the world, posing with a basketball. But he doesn&amp;rsquo;t even play basketball. He just holds it for photographs. It&amp;rsquo;s like that guy who says he&amp;rsquo;s crazy about football, only he never watches the games, doesn&amp;rsquo;t know the rules, it just pops into his mind every once in a while.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In the twilight of GMT+1</title>
      <link>http://marshallmallicoat.com/2015/02/02/in-the-twilight.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>MM</author>
      <guid>http://marshallmallicoat.com/2015/02/02/in-the-twilight.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The telegraph was an early internet, with its own lolcats and leetspeak. To people in the future, we probly seem like steampunks: one foot in the last century, carrying our brains around in our pockets like Tamagotchis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To open a file on your computer, you touch an arrowhead to a tiny picture of a manila folder. When you want to save, an artist&amp;rsquo;s rendering of a 3.5” floppy disk. Clicking on a trashcan will de-index a block of memory. If the world was Tetris, we&amp;rsquo;d all have roofs with holes in them (or no roofs at all). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buddhist prayers wheels have a mantra written around so that, when spun, it is like the mantra is being read. The Dalai Lama has said that having the mantra on your computer works the same as a traditional wheel. As the digital image spins on your hard drive, it sends the peaceful prayer of compassion in all directions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Malaysian space agency recommends that Muslim astronauts, if they cannot determine the direction of Mecca, pray in the direction of the Earth. Failing that, any direction is acceptable. Additionally they advise you to &amp;ldquo;observe peace with other beings&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Tibet and Nepal, they still practice sky burials, where bodies are stripped and laid out for the vultures to eat. But the bodies that have been given medicine or cleaned in hospitals make the vultures sick, so they have to be buried in the ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently the most coveted donors for knee replacements are Muslim men. Their patella are kept flexible by the years of praying on their knees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have never been middle-aged rappers before. And you can&amp;rsquo;t even make a rapper admit to rapping anymore. They&amp;rsquo;ve become demure. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember when pay phones cost 35 cents. I remember pay phones. I asked around and confirmed that they don&amp;rsquo;t even play beer pong with beer in the cups anymore. They just keep score on paper. We will be among the last people on Earth to remember before the Internet, if yet we still do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My brief roommate</title>
      <link>http://marshallmallicoat.com/2015/01/05/lorraine.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>MM</author>
      <guid>http://marshallmallicoat.com/2015/01/05/lorraine.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Her name is Lorraine, like the motel where Martin Luther King was shot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Long tangled hair, grey-brown. Bad teeth. 52 and haggard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The kind of woman who coughs and hacks and spits in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her diet: milk, whitebread, mayonnaise, corn, canned tuna, boiled hotdogs, hamburger buns, instant decaf coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Calls me Marshall or Matthew or Michael and, only once, Raymond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frequently offers me food, which I decline.
&lt;/br&gt;&amp;#8226; Fruit snacks (“They got Vitamin C.”)
&lt;/br&gt;&amp;#8226; Coca-Cola (“It&amp;rsquo;s fresh!”)
&lt;/br&gt;&amp;#8226; Crackers (“Whole wheat.”)
&lt;/br&gt;&amp;#8226; Chicken giblets (“They&amp;rsquo;re tough. They&amp;rsquo;ll make you strong!”)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Has one of those plastic pill trays with compartments for MORN, NOON, EVE, and BED.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a phone or a computer. The woman who keeps her money was supposed to set her up with a TV and a cellphone but hasn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her friends generally get her attention by standing in front of the building and yelling her name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the neighborhood where we live, there are wild roaming chihuahuas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Used to work sweeping floors, but now no longer works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asks me a few times a day for 50 cents, to buy loosies from the corner store. We keep a running tab. I promised myself I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t give her more than $5, but eventually she wore me down. She&amp;rsquo;ll have money for me on the first of the month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Has a boyfriend, who is apparently French and a carpenter. Sometimes she helps him in some capacity, for which he pays her in McDonald&amp;rsquo;s. He also lets her wash her pissy clothes at his place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asked me to buy cocaine for her once, but I said no.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some things she says:
&lt;/br&gt;&amp;#8226; “Oh, yeeaahh?” (face scrunches up like a chipmunk)
&lt;/br&gt;&amp;#8226; “Wooow” (breathless awe; can be said after any statement, e.g. &lt;em&gt;L: “Do you have a car?” M: &amp;ldquo;Yeah.” L: “Wooow. What color is it?” M: “Green.” L: “Wooow.”&lt;/em&gt;)
&lt;/br&gt;&amp;#8226; “Can I borrow fifty cents, baby?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is somewhat pleasant to talk to, considering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smoked inside the apartment until I told her to stop, then continues to smoke inside when I&amp;rsquo;m not around. Uses a little crystal swan as an ashtray.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brought a stray cat into the apartment. I made her kick it out, but she still lays out little dishes on the floor for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s milk souring somewhere where I can&amp;rsquo;t find.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know if she has the cat hidden away somewhere or if she is keeping an imaginary cat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have since moved out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Currency</title>
      <link>http://marshallmallicoat.com/2014/12/01/currency.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>MM</author>
      <guid>http://marshallmallicoat.com/2014/12/01/currency.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;People make light of the weird pyramid on the back of the one dollar bill (and the floating Eye above it)&amp;mdash;but they never mention the blighted little shrubs at its foot, or the miasmas rising from the cracked landscape behind.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can fold the twenty dollar bill in such a way that the low barberry hedges behind the White House transform into smoke billowing from the World Trade. And a quarter has 119 ridges on the edge [called &lt;em&gt;reeds&lt;/em&gt;], which we all know is 9/11 backwards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The back of the Susan B. Anthony dollar coin shows a bald eagle clutching a laurel branch, flying above the surface of the moon. But of course there is no air for an eagle to breathe on the moon and no wind to lift his wings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It says, &lt;em&gt;This note is legal tender for all debts, public and private.&lt;/em&gt; Thus the balance in my bank account means I am owed a great debt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the base of FDR&amp;rsquo;s neck on the dime, there are the initials &lt;em&gt;JS&lt;/em&gt; embossed in tiny letters. At one time, people suspected this stood for &lt;em&gt;Joseph Stalin&lt;/em&gt;, placed there by a Soviet agent at the mint. They are actually the initials of the designer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Samuel Curtis Upham (1819-1885) was a famed counterfeiter of Confederate bills. During the rebellion, he printed millions and sold them for pennies on the dollar. In his lifetime, he was known as Honest Sam Upham.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;One in every ten thousand American bills in circulation is counterfeit. The thing about being covered in cocaine is true. The Confederate dollar was fiat currency 100 years before the US dollar. Your unredeemed Camel Cash expired in 2007 and is worthless.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Apparently all of the gold ever mined would fill a cube 66 feet by 66 feet by 66 feet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ten Crack Commandments with taglines from the X-Files</title>
      <link>http://marshallmallicoat.com/2014/11/03/crack-commandments.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>MM</author>
      <guid>http://marshallmallicoat.com/2014/11/03/crack-commandments.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Never let no one know how much dough you hold&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;The truth is out there&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Never let them know your next move&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;Deny everything&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Never trust nobody&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;Trust no one&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Never get high on your own supply&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;I want to believe&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Never sell no crack where you rest at&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;Apology is policy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;That goddamn credit, dead it&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;Resist or serve&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Keep your family and business completely separated&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;Everything dies&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Never keep no weight on you&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;They&amp;rsquo;re watching&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you ain&amp;rsquo;t getting bags, stay the fuck from police&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;Believe to understand&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A strong word called consignment: strictly for live men, not freshmen&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;Nothing important happened today&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If you buy the car, you get to kick the tires</title>
      <link>http://marshallmallicoat.com/2014/10/13/kick-the-tires.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>MM</author>
      <guid>http://marshallmallicoat.com/2014/10/13/kick-the-tires.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Long Vacation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I quit my insurance job for another insurance job in Hartford, Conn. I packed everything I own into the Buick that my grampa left me&amp;mdash;my beautiful big body Buick&amp;mdash;and drove 100 miles deeper into New England.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My stock farewell for exes and departing friends has been, &lt;em&gt;see you later&lt;/em&gt;. I like to imagine we will meet again, if the world requires it, if only at the resurrection of the dead. My last day at work didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like anything more than the last day before a long vacation, from which I would inevitably return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quebec via Blandford&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Between jobs, I went on a road trip to Quebec. I figured Quebec was the closest thing to a foreign country that I could get to for $100. Passing thru Blandford, Mass., I saw a foreboding sign warning of “Low Flying Planes”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you found yourself naked on the side of a highway in, say, the Adirondacks, what one item would you want with you? Your cell phone? Your wallet? A gun? Shoes?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hostel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In French Canada, Starbucks is called Caf&amp;eacute; Starbucks. The detour sign says &lt;em&gt;D&amp;eacute;tour&lt;/em&gt;. The deer sign is the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hostel feels like a college dorm. It smells like a college dorm. I slept in a room with five damp Frenchmen. The steam from the attached shower completed our locker room. We mostly laid in the dark and looked at our respective smartphones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having quit drinking, there is an empty space in my life, and it&amp;rsquo;s shaped like a pub crawl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Montreal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent the morning at the university library. I walked in the front door and found a seat in the study area. I was questioned by a security guard, but I just pretended to have forgotten my student ID and he relented. There was only one other person there, on a whole floor of long tables and dim cubicles&amp;mdash;and he had probly just come in off the street too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At a fancy vegan restaurant, I was given a ginger-root beet-juice drink by mistake. I took a sip, knowing it was a mistake, but suppressing this knowledge. I hoped it was somehow complementary or part of the tofu sandwich I had ordered, tho it was nowhere on the menu. The waitstaff discovered their error and suggested I pay for the drink, which I had by then drank. I complied, thinking it couldn&amp;rsquo;t cost that much, and ended up spending 8,95 CAD on some thin red wet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Montreal 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Downtown Montreal feels like a clean, depopulated Manhattan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stepped into a biblioteque anarchiste just to browse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This city, like all cities, has been weaponized against transients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quebec City&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I drove thru a brown landscape that reminded me more of Iowa than France. I was doing 120 in the 100km/h.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The old part of Quebec looks like Europe for someone who has never been to Europe, which I haven&amp;rsquo;t. The facade of the buildings are kept as they were, but inside there are T-shirt shops. It&amp;rsquo;s like Colonial Williamsburg without the pre-diabetic wheelwright going on about the Stamp Act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked in from the rain to a cathedral&amp;mdash;the oldest in America north of Mexico&amp;mdash;and I took off my hat in a gesture of reverence. But it felt ridiculous. Why this reverence? For this so-called House-o-God, built by forced labor, on stolen land, with stone tore up out the ground, and gold leaf by way of Senegal, etc., etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In making monuments of the oldest settlements, we venerate scar tissue, while the new wounds still bleed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Border Crossing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the border, I propped my door open to talk, since my window won&amp;rsquo;t go down. The guy took the opportunity to shake it back and forth, I suppose to detect hidden contraband. Border guards are always suspicious when you are an American returning to America. (Only now do I wonder about my Fourth Amendment.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They ask you basic questions like “Where do you live?” but in a pointed way, like they expect anyone other than an upright citizen to be unable to respond. And however commonplace the answer, they take it with exaggerated incredulity. I told him I was on vacation, and he goes “&lt;em&gt;Alone?&lt;/em&gt;” with a little grin. I guess they want to rattle you, to see what falls out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He looked at me hard and then at the row of cars behind and conceded to his gut&amp;rsquo;s calculus. He was disappointed to let me go.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>His friends called him Jay</title>
      <link>http://marshallmallicoat.com/2014/09/01/called-him-jay.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>MM</author>
      <guid>http://marshallmallicoat.com/2014/09/01/called-him-jay.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A mover&amp;rsquo;s joke:&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Mover: Where&amp;rsquo;s the apartment?&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Man: It&amp;rsquo;s up on the second floor.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Mover: It always is&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A parking ticket citation: &amp;ldquo;This car been seat there to long.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A headline I saw: &lt;em&gt;If you read one article on Obamacare today, make it this one.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A classified ad: BBW seeks more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Russian joke from the Soviet period:&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;[Regarding a man lying in the middle of the street.]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Comrade: His lethargic display of apathy and lack of industry is shameful!&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Comrade: It is a legitimate response to the harsh and inconsequential nature of being. I celebrate his tenacity!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An observation: The weather is not news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A suspicion: They play horseshoes for money in the park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MDCCLXXVI: 1776.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Logion 72 from the Gospel of Thomas, Lambdin translation:&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;A man said to Jesus: &amp;ldquo;Tell my brothers that they have to divide my father’s possessions with me.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Jesus said to him: &amp;ldquo;Oh man, who has made me a divider?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Jesus turned to his disciples and said to them: &amp;ldquo;I am not a divider, am I?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something you notice: Your workplace has the same faucets as your childhood home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s more: Parking garages are laid out like a double helix, with pathways in the middle of each level to cross to the other branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neither here nor there: Water tastes better thru a black straw.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greetings from the Golden Corral</title>
      <link>http://marshallmallicoat.com/2014/08/03/greetings-from.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>MM</author>
      <guid>http://marshallmallicoat.com/2014/08/03/greetings-from.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have certain information to share with you. I recently moved into a room separated from a smaller room by drywall. Where I can hear someone shifting around inside, listening to the BBC World Service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can tell you that horses are measured in &lt;em&gt;hands&lt;/em&gt;. The tallest being over 20 hands high. Also: the nub on a horse&amp;rsquo;s leg&amp;mdash;a vestigial thumb&amp;mdash;is called the &lt;em&gt;chestnut&lt;/em&gt;. And the bottom of a horse&amp;rsquo;s hoof is called the &lt;em&gt;frog&lt;/em&gt;. (Truly.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I submit that the horse is the only animal that wears shoes, tho not by choice. The police horse is the only animal with a job it hates. Their big eyes are foggy with anomie, bowels inflamed with the heightened contradictions of the capitalist state. Working horses are kept blindered, and their internet browsing closely monitored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By classical conditioning, a pigeon can be made to play the first two bars of &amp;ldquo;Dixie&amp;rdquo; on a thumb piano. Dogs can be taught to sniff out drugs. Honeybees can smell contraband better than dogs, and at less cost, but the public still doesn&amp;rsquo;t trust bees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My brother got a lab assistant job at a medical testing center in Stilwell, Kan. They specialize in animal trials. They use mice, rats, beagles, and Crab-Eating Macaques.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of his job is to play with the monkeys. He blows bubbles with them, turns on a movie or some music. They like &lt;em&gt;Finding Nemo&lt;/em&gt; and bluegrass. The Crab-Eating Macaque doesn&amp;rsquo;t eat crabs usually, but will if they&amp;rsquo;re available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a little chair to tie them down for injections. Some of the monkeys have microchips implanted to measure their blood pressure. They&amp;rsquo;re given medication with a device called a &lt;em&gt;pill gun&lt;/em&gt;. It perforated the throat of a monkey, once, and the monkey had to be put down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve caught fish and thrown them back, but I&amp;rsquo;ve never had the chance to kill an animal with righteousness. To put down a hurt dog, to crush a snake with a shovel, or even burn a brown recluse with a matchstick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My brother says he could never have a pet beagle.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    

  </channel> 
</rss>
